Guide to the Yale College Records of the Dean
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Yale College records of the dean
1857-2015
RU 126
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
534
77.5
The records consist of correspondence, memoranda, subject, administrative and digital files, minutes, and financial reports documenting the activities of the dean of Yale College.
Yale College (1887- ). Dean's Office
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 9-A (YRG 9-A), Central records and records of the dean of Yale College.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the materials is partially restricted. See inventory for details.
Original born digital files, as well as preservation masters, may not be accessed due to their fragility. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist request that they be made. Born digital files cannot be accessed remotely. System requirements include a Manuscripts and Archives computer and file viewing software.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by accession.
Biographical / Historical
The Yale College dean's office was established during Timothy Dwight's presidency (1886-1899). The office was created in order to assist the president in his administrative duties, and to aid the faculty in social and disciplinary matters. The dean oversees the general course of study, administrative policies, and the operations of such programs as Directed Studies, Expository Writing, and Scholars of the House. The dean is also responsible for policies affecting campus life, student discipline, student organizations, and affairs concerning the masters of the residential colleges. The dean is the chief administrator of Yale College and oversees the Yale College faculty. The Yale College dean holds membership on the Executive Committee, the Course of Study Committee, most standing committees in Yale College, the Executive Committee of the Faculty of Arts and Sciences, and the Junior and Senior Faculty Appointments Committees.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of correspondence, memoranda, subject, administrative and digital files, minutes, and financial reports documenting the activities of the dean of Yale College.
Deans (Education); Universities and colleges -- Administration; Altman, Sidney; DeVane, William C. (William Clyde), 1898-1965; Jones, Frederick Scheetz, 1862-1944; Lamar, Howard Roberts, 1923-; May, Georges, 1920-; Taft, Horace Dwight, 1925-1983; Wright, Henry Parks, 1839-1918; Yale College (1887- ). Administration; Yale College (1887- ). Dean's Office; Yale University -- Administration; Yale University -- Students
- Records, 1857-1928; Accession 1935-A-003
  Conditions Governing Access
  The materials are open for research.
  - Correspondence, Chronological, 1869-1918, undated
    - 1869-1879 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - 1882-1899 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - 1900-1901 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - 1902 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - 1903 Jan-May (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - 1903 Jun-Dec (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - 1904 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - 1905 Jan 1 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - 1905 Jan-Jun (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - 1905 Jul-Dec (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - 1906 Jan-May (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - 1906 Jun-Dec (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - 1907 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - 1908 Jan-Apr (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - 1908 May-Dec (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - 1909 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - 1910-1912 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - 1913-1918 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - no date (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Subject Files, 1881-1917
    - Academic budget, 1905-1914 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Alumni Affairs, 1910, 1917 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Association of Colleges of New England: minutes, 1906- 1909 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Athletics, 1896-1905 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Clubs, societies and ceremonies, 1896-1904 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Committees (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Connecticut College for Women: Report of the Committee to Nominate a President Re: Frederick Henry Sykes (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Curriculum, 1801, 1892-1911 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Faculty records; resolutions, 1900-1906, undated (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Juvenal, 1901-1910 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Newspaper correspondents (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Office procedures, undated (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Preparatory schools (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Price of rooms (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Riot of 1841 (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Scholarships and funds, 1902-1906 (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - Student attendance (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Summer school, 1907 (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - Union-Confederate Civil War Memorial, 1909-1913 (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Vitae (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - Yale Association of Class Secretaries: minutes, 1903 April 20 (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - Yale-in-China
      - Correspondence, 1901-1909 (Box 3, Folder 41)
      - Correspondence, 1910-1911, undated (Box 3, Folder 42)
      - Photographs (Box 3, Folder 43)
      - Reports, Publications, Constitution, 1905-1911 (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - Petition, 1891 November 17 (Box 4)
  - Grade and Attendance Notebooks, Office Diaries, 1886-1907
    - Diary of Dean's Office activities
      - 1886-1893 (Box 5, Folder 45)
      - 1903-1906 (Box 5, Folder 46)
      - 1902-1907 (Box 5, Folder 47)
    - Notes re: Yale College, undated (Box 5, Folder 48)
    - Junior and Senior classes
      - 1884 Sep-1885 Jun (Box 6, Folder 49)
      - 1885 Sep-1886 Jun (Box 6, Folder 50)
      - 1886 Sep-1887 Jun (Box 6, Folder 51)
      - 1887 Sep-1888 Jun (Box 6, Folder 52)
      - 1888 Sep-1889 Jun (Box 6, Folder 53)
      - 1889 Sep-1890 Jun (Box 6, Folder 54)
      - 1890 Sep-1891 Jun (Box 6, Folder 55)
      - 1891 Sep-1892 Jun (Box 6, Folder 56)
      - Freshman Term, 1893 (Box 6, Folder 57)
      - 1886 Mar-1892 Jun (Box 7, Folder 58)
    - Student records
      - 1885 (Box 7, Folder 59)
      - 1872-1886 (Box 7, Folder 60)
      - 1890 (Box 7, Folder 61)
      - 1892 (Box 7, Folder 62)
      - 1893 (Box 8, Folder 63)
      - 1884 (Box 8, Folder 64)
  - Speeches, Notes, Biographical Clippings, Photographs
    - The Young Man and Teaching: drafts and notes, undated (Box 9, Folder 65)
    - From School Through College: notes, undated (Box 9, Folder 66)
    - Greek examinations, undated (Box 9, Folder 67)
    - Eulogy of Jim Hogan, undated (Box 9, Folder 68)
    - Education at Andover, undated (Box 9, Folder 69)
    - "Christianity, The True Philosophy'', 1868 (Box 9, Folder 70)
    - Seabury, Warren, 1900 (Box 9, Folder 71)
    - Talk to class of, 1901 (Box 9, Folder 72)
    - Education: speech at Lakeville (Hotchkiss School), undated (Box 9, Folder 73)
    - Getting the most out of college education, undated (Box 9, Folder 74)
    - Supporting the Alumni Association, undated (Box 9, Folder 75)
    - Phillips, Andrew Wheeler Tribute, undated (Box 9, Folder 76)
    - Commonplace book, undated (Box 9, Folder 77)
    - Educational preparation, undated (Box 9, Folder 78)
    - Instruction, undated (Box 9, Folder 79)
    - Government, undated (Box 9, Folder 80)
    - Latin studies, undated (Box 9, Folder 81)
    - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 9, Folder 82)
    - Teachers, undated (Box 9, Folder 83)
    - Outside activities, undated (Box 9, Folder 84)
    - "The Chrisitian Missionary": paper delivered before The Society of Inquiry, Phillips Academy, I857 September 24 (Box 9, Folder 85)
    - Report of the committees on China: paper delivered before the Society of Inquiry, Phillips Academy, 1859 May 26 (Box 9, Folder 86)
    - "Observatory": delivered before the Society of Inquity, Phillips Academy, 1861 October 31 (Box 9, Folder 87)
    - "Criticism": delivered at the Linophilian Society, Monson Academy, 1860 May 22 (Box 9, Folder 88)
    - "Criticism": delivered before the Philomathean Society, Phillips Academy, 1862 May 2 (Box 9, Folder 89)
    - "Constantine": class composition, Phillips Academy, 1862 May 30 (Box 9, Folder 90)
    - "Algernon Sydney Biddle": paper read before the Pennsylvania Society of the Revolution by J. Granville Leach, undated (Box 9, Folder 91)
    - "The College and the University" by L.O. Bergh, 1906 (Box 9, Folder 92)
    - A.L. to E.B. Monroe, positive photostat, 1885 May 30 (Box 9, Folder 93)
    - Address to Henry Parks Wright upon his retirement as Dean by Professor Bernadotte Perrin, 1909 June 25 (Box 9, Folder 94)
    - Letters of sympathy to family members, 1918 (Box 9, Folder 95)
    - To Mrs. Wright on Class of 1868 reunion, 1928 June-July (Box 9, Folder 96)
    - Re: Dean Henry Parks Wright, undated (Box 9, Folder 97)
    - 51st Massachusetts Regiment, undated (Box 9, Folder 98)
    - Photographs: Latin manuscript page, undated (Box 9, Folder 99)
    - Photographs: Study, 409 Humphrey Street, New Haven, undated (Box 9, Folder 100)
  - Lecture Notes, Latin Research Notes, Account Books
    - Latin Studies, undated (Box 10, Folder 101 - 105)
    - "Some account of Pliny the Younger and his age, from his correspondence", undated (Box 11, Folder 106)
    - Natural philosophy lectures delivered by Elias Loomis, undated (Box 11, Folder 107)
    - Account book
      - 1865 Sep-Dec (Box 11, Folder 108)
      - 1909 Jul-1910 Sep (Box 11, Folder 109)
      - 1909 Dec-1910 Oct (Box 11, Folder 110)
    - Plaque: 25 Years of Service as Dean (Box 12)
    - Photograph portrait of Henry Parks Wright (Box 13)
- Records, 1895-1938; Accession 1940-A-004
  - General Correspondence, 1909-1910
    - A-B (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - C-D (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - E-G (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - H-J (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - K-L (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - M (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - M-Q (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - R- S (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - T-V (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - W-Z (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Student Correspondence, 1911-1924
    - A-B (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - C-F (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - G-K (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - L-O (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - P-R (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - S (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - T-Z (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Subject Files, 1895-1936
    - American Association of University Professors (AAUP), 1928 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - American Real Estate Co., 1920 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Andover, 1913-1917 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Angell, President, 1923-1926 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Arkansas, University of, 1913 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - ATandT, 1920 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Budget
      - 1921-1922 (Box 3, Folder 24 - 25)
      - 1924 (Box 3, Folder 26)
      - 1925-1926 (Box 3, Folder 27 - 28)
    - Bureau of Appointments, 1925 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Chapel: Battell, 1918-1926 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Class lists and averages, 1925-1930 (Box 3, Folder 31 - 34)
    - Class of 1922 (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - Class of 1924 (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Class of 1925 (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - Class of 1926 (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - Class of 1927 (Box 4, Folder 39)
    - Class of 1928 (Box 4, Folder 40)
    - Class of 1929 (Box 4, Folder 41)
    - Committee on Aids to Research, 1927 (Box 4, Folder 42)
    - Committee on Course of Study, 1925-1926 (Box 4, Folder 43)
    - Committee on the Educational Needs of Yale College, 1923-1924 (Box 4, Folder 44)
    - Courses, undergraduate and graduate, listed by professor [See also: Box 5, Folders 67-70], 1915 November - 1917 March (Box 4, Folder 45 - 48)
    - Disciplinary committees (Box 4, Folder 49)
    - Dormitory rules, 1922 (Box 4, Folder 50)
    - Electives, 1922-1923 (Box 4, Folder 51)
    - Enrollment, 1917-1924 (Box 4, Folder 52)
    - Examinations: mid-year, 1923 (Box 4, Folder 53)
    - Faculty, 1910-1926 (Box 4, Folder 54 - 55)
    - Fellowships, 1923-1924 (Box 4, Folder 56)
    - Fraternities, 1917-1929 (Box 4, Folder 57)
    - Goddard, John Calvin, 1926 (Box 5, Folder 58)
    - Goodell, Thomas D., 1915 (Box 5, Folder 59)
    - Grounds and Buildings, 1899-1926 (Box 5, Folder 60 - 63)
    - Harkness gift, 1917-1918 (Box 5, Folder 64)
    - Harkness quadrangle cornerstone laying, 1917 (Box 5, Folder 65)
    - Harkness, William H.: educational building, 1917-1926 (Box 5, Folder 66)
    - Harvard verses, 1915-1924 (Box 5, Folder 67)
    - Honor system, 1926 (Box 5, Folder 68)
    - International-school student registration correspondence re: changes between Yale College and other Yale schools, 1914 September - 1915 (Box 5, Folder 69 - 71)
    - International-school student registration financial summaries of changes between Yale College and other Yale schools, 1914-1917 (Box 5, Folder 72)
    - Jews, 1911-1925 (Box 6, Folder 73)
    - Keith, Allen, 1924 (Box 7, Folder 74)
    - Keller, Professor Albert G., 1909-1918 (Box 7, Folder 75)
    - Lowell, Lawrence -- Harvard, 1910-1911 (Box 7, Folder 76)
    - McClellan, Hall, 1920-1925 (Box 7, Folder 77)
    - Medical School, 1910-1923 (Box 7, Folder 78)
    - Miller, George D. (Elliot Corporation), 1919-1920 (Box 7, Folder 79)
    - Miscellaneous, 1913-1919 (Box 7, Folder 80)
    - Murphy, John Speed Scholarship, 1925 (Box 7, Folder 81)
    - Princeton, 1920 (Box 7, Folder 82)
    - Prizes and scholarships, 1910-1924 (Box 7, Folder 83)
    - Proctors' dormitory, 1921-1924 (Box 7, Folder 84)
    - Reorganization, 1919 (Box 7, Folder 85)
    - Resignations, 1915-1930 (Box 7, Folder 86)
    - Schedule of examinations, 1933 (Box 7, Folder 87)
    - Scholarships, 1924-1926 (Box 7, Folder 88)
    - Statistics
      - 1924-1935 (Box 7, Folder 89)
      - Elections, 1895-1933 (Box 8, Folder 90)
      - Scholarship, 1915-1938 (Box 8, Folder 91)
    - Taylor, Andrew S., 1914-1915 (Box 8, Folder 92)
    - Temperance and prohibition, 1914-1925 (Box 8, Folder 93)
    - Vice, Society for the Suppression of, 1916 (Box 8, Folder 94)
    - War
      - Correspondence and resolutions, 1916-1918 (Box 8, Folder 95)
      - Yale students enlisted in Aerial Observation Unit (Kite Balloon Unit), undated (Box 8, Folder 96)
      - Yale students enlisted in: correspondence, 1917 March-December (Box 8, Folder 97 - 99)
      - Yale students enlisted in: lists, 1917 (Box 8, Folder 100)
    - Wright Memorial, 1910-1911 (Box 8, Folder 101)
- Records of William Clyde Devane as dean, 1913-1965; Accession 1964-A-003
  - Subject-Correspondence File
    - Allocations to the colleges, suggested plans of, 1942, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - American Studies: survey of programs, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Automobile registration and insurance for students, 1956-1959 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Aviation, 1927-1933 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - B.A. degree, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Bowl, Yale: report on completion of, 1929 August (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Broadcasting system: proposal for, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Carbon 14 dating laboratory, 1950-1952 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Chess Club rules, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Yale Cinema annual report, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Civil pilot training, 1940-1942 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Yale-Clare scholarships, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Class Ivies (list corrected), 1928 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Class of 1963, dedication of classbook to WCD (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Classification test, Yale: report on further investigation of college success and its predictability, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Classroom attendance, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Colleges (jurisdiction between the schools, colleges, and departments), 1934-1940 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Connecticut Hall, restoration of, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Corinthian Yacht Club, 1943, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Correspondence - Connecticut College, 1919-1924 (Box 1, Folder 19a)
    - Degrees, reports on, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Directed Studies
      - Correspondence and clippings, 1948-1949 (Box 1, Folder 21)
      - Literature I, 1948-1949 (Box 2, Folder 22)
      - Philosophy I and II, report on, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 23)
      - Philosophy I and II, planned assignments, 1948-1949 (Box 2, Folder 24)
      - Philosophy I, plan and assignments, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 25)
      - Sophomore year, report on, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 26)
      - Report on, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 27)
      - Statistics and budget, 1948-1949 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Divisional major programs, requirements, 1947, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Dramatic Association, TLS from Arthur F. Jenks to George H. Nettleton, 1913 March 27 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Economics, Department of, 1938-1941 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Education, reports on, 1930-1966 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Educational Planning, Committee on, 1939-1944 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Examinations, policies regarding, 1932-1941 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Faculty, general, 1927-1950 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Foreign languages
      - Correspondence, 1944-1945 (Box 2, Folder 36)
      - Publications, 1944-1945 (Box 2, Folder 37)
      - Reports, 1944-1945 (Box 2, Folder 38)
      - Russian, 1934-1943 (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - Fraternities, 1928-1952 (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - "The Future Yale College", 1928 (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - Geography: economic, 1939 (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - German Universities: report by Kenneth MacLean, 1928 (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - Grading system, 1932-1939 (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - Harvard Society of Fellows, 1933 (Box 3, Folder 45)
    - History Department, 1934 (Box 3, Folder 46)
    - Honors Committee, 1927-1929 (Box 3, Folder 47)
    - Honor system: fact finding committee, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 48)
    - Hoyt Memorial Fund, 1939-1947 (Box 3, Folder 49)
    - Intercollegiate scholastic competition, 1921-1927 (Box 3, Folder 50)
    - Jewish holy days, 1943 (Box 3, Folder 51)
    - Johson, Robert Livington: Petition for credit for war service, 1941 (Box 3, Folder 52)
    - Jones, Frederick Sheetz: biographical sketch, 1936 (Box 3, Folder 53)
    - Liberal education, 1942-1943 (Box 3, Folder 54)
    - Majors, 1935-1945 (Box 3, Folder 55)
    - Mendell, Clarence Whitlesey: Dean, 1926-1937 (Box 3, Folder 56)
    - Modern Language Association, 1939-1944 (Box 3, Folder 57)
    - Offices: floor plans, 1945 (Box 3, Folder 58)
    - Phi Beta Kappa, 1942-1950 (Box 3, Folder 60)
    - Physical education, 1942-1960 (Box 3, Folder 61)
    - Physics Department, 1943-1944 (Box 4, Folder 62)
    - Pierson College, 1960-1963 (Box 4, Folder 63)
    - Political Union, 1945 (Box 4, Folder 64)
    - Prizes, 1941-1948 (Box 4, Folder 65)
    - Yale publications, 1937 (Box 4, Folder 66)
    - Reading lists for majors, 1949-1952 (Box 4, Folder 67)
    - Reading lists for Yale servicemen, 1940-1946 (Box 4, Folder 68)
    - Reading periods, 1930-1940 (Box 4, Folder 69)
    - Registrar: report of, 1936-1937 (Box 4, Folder 70)
    - "Registration for undergraduate schools": Director of, 1944-1945 (Box 4, Folder 71)
    - Regulations of Yale College, undated (Box 4, Folder 72)
    - Religion: reports on, 1951 (Box 4, Folder 73)
    - Requirements for degree, 1945 (Box 4, Folder 74)
    - Reserve Midshipmen's Course, 1940 (Box 4, Folder 75)
    - Reserve Officers Training Corp: Naval, 1945 (Box 4, Folder 76)
    - Reserve Officers Training Corp: programs, 1916-1962 (Box 4, Folder 77)
    - Residential Colleges, 1931-1940 (Box 4, Folder 78)
    - S correspondence, 1939-1947 (Box 4, Folder 80)
    - Scholars of the House, 1949 (Box 4, Folder 81)
    - Senior societies, 1941 (Box 4, Folder 82)
    - Shakespeare birthday celebration, 1938 April 23 (Box 4, Folder 83)
    - Sheffield Scientific School and School of Engineering, undated (Box 4, Folder 84)
    - Sick excuses: problem of, 1947 (Box 4, Folder 85)
    - Student records and admissions (Cresak report), 1949 (Box 4, Folder 86)
    - Social Science Club, undated (Box 4, Folder 87)
    - Southeast Asia Studies, 1949-1950 (Box 4, Folder 88)
    - Statistics, 1937-1947 (Box 5, Folder 89)
    - Student conference group, 1937-1942 (Box 5, Folder 90)
    - Student council, 1928, 1941 (Box 5, Folder 91)
    - Studies in Society, Research project re: Elm Haven housing project, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 92)
    - Treasurer's office, 1926-1941 (Box 5, Folder 93)
    - Undergraduate Activities Committee, 1945 (Box 5, Folder 94)
    - Undergraduate reorganization: Committee on, 1927-1928 (Box 5, Folder 95)
    - Whitney Fellows: (John Hay), 1953-1963 (Box 5, Folder 96)
    - Wright Memorial, undated (Box 5, Folder 97)
  - Non-Yale Organizations
    - American Council of Learned Societies, 1943-1952 (Box 6, Folder 1 - 11)
    - Appleton-Century Crofts, Inc., 1957-1965 (Box 7, Folder 12 - 15)
    - Aspen Institute for Humanistic Studies, 1964-1965 (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Carnegie General Education Program: internships
      - 1950-1953 (Box 7, Folder 17 - 18)
      - 1953-1959 (Box 8, Folder 19 - 21)
    - Center for information on America, 1960-1965 (Box 8, Folder 22 - 23)
    - Dean's group, 1949-1963 (Box 8, Folder 24 - 26)
    - General Education Board, 1952-1963 (Box 8, Folder 27 - 28)
    - Humanities, Visiting Committee on the Department of, 1965 (Box 9, Folder 29)
    - Modern Language Association Center: Advisory conference on, 1963 (Box 9, Folder 30)
    - New Haven College, 1961-1962 (Box 9, Folder 31)
    - University of Pennsylvania Press, 1963 (Box 9, Folder 35)
    - Phi Beta Kappa
      - 1962-1965 (Box 9, Folder 36 - 38)
      - 1962-1965 (Box 10, Folder 39 - 42)
    - Advanced religious studies: program of, 1955 (Box 10, Folder 43)
    - Wells College, 1956-1963 (Box 10, Folder 44)
  - Military Training Programs
    - Class lists, honor rolls, 1943-1945 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Classification board minutes, 1943-1945 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - "Company A Mitre", "Company F Informant", 1943-1949 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, reports, news releases
      - 1943 (Box 11, Folder 4 - 9)
      - 1943-1944 (Box 12, Folder 10 - 13)
    - Course schedules, undated (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Curricula, 1941-1945 (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - Faculty, regulations, reports, 1943-1944 (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - Headquarters, Army Service Forces: memoranda, 1943-1945 (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - "Irregular" V-12 Deck: Term III, Units I, II, 1944 (Box 13, Folder 18)
    - Publications, 1941-1944 (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - Requirements, schedule changes, 1943-1945 (Box 13, Folder 20)
    - Special orders: transcripts, 1943-1944 (Box 13, Folder 21)
    - Student lists, 1943-1944 (Box 13, Folder 22)
    - Navy programs: questionnaire responses, 1943 (Box 13, Folder 23)
    - Correspondence, reports, news releases, 1941-1942 (Box 13, Folder 24 - 26)
    - Correspondence, curriculum, lists, reports
      - no date (Box 13, Folder 27)
      - no date (Box 14, Folder 28)
    - Correspondence, minutes, reports, 1944 (Box 14, Folder 29 - 31)
  - Associate Dean's Files
    - Board of Admissions, 1951-1952 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Bureau of Appointments, 1947-1954 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Choate School, 1949 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Connecticut Council on Higher Education, 1948-1956 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Dean's office procedure manual, undated (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Directed Studies Survey, 1949-1956 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Dean's Honor List, 1943-1945 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Eligibility Committee, 1958-1959 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Executive Committee minutes, 1943-1957 (Box 16, Folder 9 - 13)
    - Financial Aid, 1946-1959 (Box 16, Folder 14)
    - Grading systen and classroom attendance, 1954 (Box 17, Folder 18)
    - Henry Fellowships, 1949-1961 (Box 17, Folder 19)
    - Hochschild Scholarship fund, 1949 (Box 17, Folder 20)
    - Honor system, 1949-1958 (Box 17, Folder 21)
    - Hotchkiss School statistics re: students, 1950-1956 (Box 17, Folder 22)
    - Major elections: statistics, 1930-1950 (Box 17, Folder 23)
    - Manners and Morals: Committee on, 1950-1951 (Box 17, Folder 24)
    - National Student Association Correspondence and Clippings, 1947 (Box 17, Folder 25 - 26)
    - National Association of Student Personnel Administrators, 1954-1957 (Box 17, Folder 27)
    - Naval Science, 1944-1953 (Box 17, Folder 28)
    - Paine, Ralph D. prize, 1943-1948 (Box 17, Folder 29)
    - Pre-professional training Pre-Law, 1954-1957 (Box 17, Folder 30)
    - President's committee on education beyond high school, 1956 (Box 17, Folder 31)